Close.
Imagine you stand on a beach.
The waves are booking in front of you and the sun is going down.
Can you see it in front of you?
Can you imagine this scene in your head?
If you can't, if you don't see anything at all in front of you,
Then you can have what is called afantasi.
It is a neurological condition where one cannot
visualize images in their head.
People with afantasi may also have a reduced ability
To imagine sounds, smells or flavors.
But one should not misunderstand it as persons with afantasi
is not as creative or good at problem solving.
Those who have the condition have adapted to it and taught themselves
to think and remember in a way that is not dependent
of visual mental images.
Some people first discover that they have afantasi much later
in life and may also be surprised that others can
see things in their head.
Today we know that the ability to visualize pictures
in its head is on a spectrum where Avantasi represents one end
with a total or close total inability to create mental images.
And on the other side of the spectrum we find hyperfantasi
Where individuals have an exceptionally good ability to create mental images.
Between these two there are a variety of different levels